Records of the Senior Vice President of Operations
World Bank Group Archives
The fonds also includes records related to budget formulation and budget review functions performed by the Office of the Management Systems and Budget (SVPMS) and its successor of the Office of the Management Systems and Budget (OPNMS) within the SVPOP/OPNSV Front Office from 1985 to 1992. The records were primarily maintained by the Senior Budget Officers of SVPMS/OPNMS, and the Senior Adviser for Lending and Budget Operations, Cosmas LinusRobless. The records focus primarily on budget formulation and review for Bank units belonging to the Operations Complex. The budget formulation records include: budget correspondence and memoranda; Operations Complex budget distribution and salary reports; Operations Complex budget proposals; Operations Complex capital budget; budget officers meeting minutes; budget submissions sent to the SVPOP/OPNSV related to the Operations Complex; staffing and consulting budgets; budget calendars and booklets prepared by the SVPMS/OPNMS; budget framework papers; business plans, work programs, budget plans, and budget contracts drafted for the Regional Vice Presidencies for fiscal years 1986 to 1995; and business plans, budget plans, work programs, and staffing records related to the vice presidencies and departments of Operations Complex for the fiscal years 1987 to 1991.
Budget plans and staffing records are also included for OVPMS/SVPMS, and for the SVPOP/OPNSV Front Office. Work program and budget reports are also included for the Management Information System (MIS) of the Operations Information Systems (SVPMI/OPNMI) Unit, and its successor Operations Information Services Division (OPNIS) of the SVPOP/OPNSV Front Office from 1985 to 1989.
Budget review records include: monthly status budget reports for the Operations Complex; reimbursement reports; mid-term perspective reports; quarterly, mid-year, third quarter, and retrospective review records for the Operations Complex for the fiscal years 1988 to 1992; and Operations Complex final expense reports.
Operations information management
The fonds also includes records related to the Operations Information Committee (OIC) from 1987 to 1990. The Operations Information Committee (OIC) was established in November 1987 to develop "Complex-wide strategies, plans, policies and investments in information and information technology which would...coordinate the management of information and information technology activities within or affecting the Operations Complex." Therecords include agenda and minutes of OIC meetings and documents and memoranda forwarded to Committee members. Also contained in the records are some minutes of meetings of the Information and Technology Advisory Committee (ITAC) and records related to the FY 90 work program of the Operation Information Services Division (OPNIS). The records are maintained by OIC Chairman Heinz Vergin, who served as the Operations Staff (OPN) Director at the time.
Transportation, telecommunication, water, and urban development records
The fonds also includes operations policy, project support records, and liaison records related to the sector departments of the: Transportation, Water, and Telecommunications Department (TWT); the Urban Projects Department (URB); the Water and Urban Development Department (WUD); and the Transportation Department (TRP) from 1975 to 1986.
The following arrangement is provisional. Records are arranged into nine series and one sub-fonds. The Transportation, telecommunication, water, and urban development sub-fonds includes records from departments that often supported more than one sector at a time and this is reflected by folders that contain records of more than one sector. As a result, the records of these departments have been placed in the Senior Vice President of Operations (SVPOP/OPNSV) fonds, whom the departments reported to, rather than separated and dispersed into their respective sector fonds.
Sub-fonds:
* Transportation, telecommunication, water, and urban development
Series:
* Records of Vice President of Operations and SVPOP J. Burke Knapp
* Records of OPNSV Moeen Qureshi
* Records of Special Assistant Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala
* Records of Senior Adviser, Lending and Budget Operations, Cosmas Linus Robless
* Front office adviser records
* Meetings Minutes of the Area Department Heads (later Operational Vice Presidents)
* Country lending and strategy records
* Budget formulation and review records
* Operations information management
Records prior to 1987 were transferred directly from SVPOP to the World Bank Group Archives and only later, in 1990 to 1991, assigned approved records retention and disposition schedules as part of the Records and Archives Management Improvement Program (RAMIP). Staff records of J. Burke Knapp were also transferred to the Archives, and later assigned approved records retention and disposition schedules as part of RAMIP. Post-1987 records were transferred to the Archives using approved records retention anddisposition schedules assigned to the Senior Vice President of Operations (OPNSV) or a Bank-wide schedule for common records.
Accruals are not expected.
* See the [J. Burke Knapp papers](http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt529034bg/admin/?query=knapp) held in the Hoover Institution Archives for World Bank records retained by Knapp.
* See Records of the Office of Operations Policy ([WB IBRD/IDA OP](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-office-of-operations-policy)).
* See records related to the Resource Mobilization ([WB IBRD/IDA CFOP](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/resource-mobilization)) function.
* See Records of the Operations (Loan) Committee ([WB IBRD/IDA LC](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-operations-loan-committee)).
* See Records of the Sector Policy and Research Vice Presidency (PREVP) and the Sector and Operations Policy Vice Presidency (OSPVP) ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_93](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-sector-policy-and-research-vice-presidency-prevp-and-sector-and-operations-policy-vice-presidency-ospvp)).
* For interviews of past Senior Vice Presidents of Operations (SVPOP/OPNSV), see the following oral histroies: [Burke Knapp](http://oralhistory.worldbank.org/person/knapp-j-burke); [Ernest Stern](http://oralhistory.worldbank.org/person/stern-ernest).
* For additional oral histories of Senior Vice President of Operations (SVPOP/OPNSV), see interviews for Burke Knapp, Ernest Stern, and Moeen Qureshi conducted by members of the World Bank History Project, see Records of the Office of the Historian - Records of the World Bank History Project - Interviews ([WB IBRD/IDA HIST-01-10](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/interviews-2)).
* See Records of individual staff members -- Ernest Stern files ([WB IBRD/IDA STAFF-10](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/ernest-stern-files)).
* See Records of individual staff members -- Moeen Qureshi files ([WB IBRD/IDA STAFF-26](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/moeen-qureshi-files)).
* Records related to the sector departments of the Operations Complex can be found in the various sector department fonds. See the 'Sector Departments' section in the [List of Fonds](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/list-of-fonds).
* Records related to the Regional Vice Presidencies (RVP) of the Operations Complex can be found in the six regional operations fonds. See the 'Regional Units' section in the [List of Fonds](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/list-of-fonds).
* See Records of the Human Resources Development and Operations Policy Vice Presidency ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_91](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-human-resources-development-and-operations-policy-vice-presidency)).
* See Records of the Office of the Chief Economist -- Records of the Office of the Vice President, Development Economics and Chief Economist and later Senior Vice President, Development Economics and Chief Economist (DECVP), ([WB IBRD/IDA DEC-03](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-office-of-vice-president-development-economics-and-chief-economist-and-later-senior-vice-president-development-economics-and-chief-economist-decvp)) for records related to Country Policy Department (CPD) and its successor of the Economic Advisory Staff (EAS).
* See Records of the Water Sector ([WB IBRD/IDA WAT](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-water-development-sector)).
Records are subject to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.
- Transportation, telecommunication, water, and urban development, 1975 - 1986 (predominantly 1978-1986); WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_106-01; 9.80 linear feet of textual records
  The Transportation, telecommunication, water, and urban development sub-fonds contains the records created by following departments: the Transportation, Water, and Telecommunications Department (TWT); the Urban Projects Department (URB); the Water and Urban Development Department (WUD); and the Transportation Department (TRP). TWT reported to the Vice President of Central Projects (CPSVP) from 1979 to 1982. URB also reported to CPSVP from 1976 to 1982. WUD and TRP subsequently reported to the Vice President of Operations Policy (OPSVP) with the termination of CPSVP in 1982.
  Published
  The sub-fonds includes operations policy and project support records from the following departments: the Transportation, Water, and Telecommunications Department (TWT) from 1978 to 1982; the Urban Projects Department (URB) from 1978 to 1982; the Water and Urban Development Department (WUD) from 1983 to 1986; and the Transportation Department (TRP) from 1983 to 1986. The sub-fonds also includes records related to liaison with external organizations, which were maintained by TWT from 1978 to 1983.
  Records were transferred to the World Bank Group Archives from the Non-Regional Information Center (NRIC).
  Accruals are not expected.
  The records in this subfonds were maintained by the Non-Regional Information Center (NRIC). The NRIC served as a centralized filing unit for the Bank, and arranged records according to Bank-wide classification schemes for the record group of administrative "central files" or "non-regional files". The NRIC served as one of multiple Information Centers for the Bank, which generally distributed the Bank's records into two main record groups: 1) general or non-regional, and 2) operational or regional. The records in this subfonds were not arranged by classification schemes or series specific to a department or division, but as a sub or sub-sub group to the larger "central files" record group. The NRIC were transferred to the custody World Bank Group Archives with the termination of NRIC in 1987.
  The departments described in this subfonds were assigned sub-group or series classification numbers from NRIC. The departments often supported more than one sector at a time and this is reflected by folders that contain records of more than one sector. As a result, the records of these departments have been placed in Senior Vice President of Operations (SVPOP/OPNSV) fonds, whom the departments reported to, rather than separated and dispersed into their respective sector fonds.
  * See Records of the Transport Development Sector ([WB IBRD/IDA TRA](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-transport-development-sector)).
  * See Records of the Urban Development Sector ([WB IBRD/IDA URB](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-urban-development-sector)).
  * See Records of the Water Development Sector ([WB IBRD/IDA WAT](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-water-development-sector)).
  Records are subject to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.
  - Operations policy and project support records, 1975 - 1986; WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_106-01-01; 8.66 linear feet of textual records
    The series includes records from: the Transportation, Water, and Telecommunications Department (TWT) from 1978 to 1982; the Urban Projects Department (URB) from 1978 to 1982; the Water and Urban Development Department (WUD) from 1983 to 1987; and the Transportation Department (TRP) from 1983 to 1987. These departments were primarily mixed sector departments, therefore, the records cover a broad range of topics, including but not limited to: highway maintenance and development; port development; railways;maritime transportation; water and sanitation systems maintenance and development; tourism services and infrastructure development; urban development; and telecommunication infrastructure and public utilities development. The records include: internal and external correspondence, including letters and memoranda; initiating memoranda; project files; project completion and audit reports; sector support and research files; sector policy papers; back to office reports (BTOs); terms of reference (TORs); and departmental publications. Records related to the Bank's Urban Project Program, which was originally launched in 1975 and supported by URB and later WUD are also included. The Urban Poverty Program records primarily include correspondence and reports related to various sector projects done in support of the program.
    Arranged by subject.
    - Operational Policy - Water Supply and Urban - PWU - Water and Wastes - 1981 / 1983 Correspondence - Volume 1, 1983-08-09 - 1983-12-12; 01057504
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTWT - Transportation Documents 1981 - 1983, 1981-01-01 - 1982-11-02; 30048821
    - Transportation, Water and Telecommunications Department - PTWT - Transportation 1981 - 1983, 1981-02-10 - 1982-06-09; 30048819
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTWT - General 1981 - 1983, 1981-01-29 - 1982-06-17; 30048818
    - Operational Policy - Water Supply and Urban - PWU - General - 1984 / 1986 Correspondence - Volume 1, 1984-02-28 - 1985-04-12; 01057499
    - Operational Policy - Water Supply and Urban Development - PWU - Water Supply and Sewerage - 1984 / 1986 Correspondence - Volume 1, 1983-01-03 - 1986-04-18; 01065170
    - Operational Policy - Water Supply and Urban Development - PWU - Research 1981 - 1983, 1983-09-23 - 1983-12-16; 01065167
    - Operational Policy - Water Supply and Urban Development - PWU - General 1981 - 1983, 1983-09-09 - 1983-11-29; 01065166
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTW - Transportations 1981 - 1983, 1982-07-21 - 1983-06-24; 01065153
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTW - Research 1981 - 1983, 1982-07-09 - 1983-07-20; 01065152
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTR - Research 1983, 1983-11-17; 01065150
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTR - General 1983, 1983-09-22 - 1983-12-19; 01065149
    - Urban Projects - PUR - Urban Poverty Documents, 1979-01-05 - 1979-11-20; 01064466
    - Operational Policy - Urban - PUR - Urban Poverty 1981 - 1983, 1981-03-03 - 1983-02-07; 01065165
    - Operational Policy - Urban - PUR - Research 1981 - 1983, 1981-04-16 - 1982-06-25; 01065163
    - Operational Policy - Urban - PUR - General Documents 1981 - 1983, 1981-03-13 - 1982-04-22; 01065162
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTWT - Research 1981 - 1983, 1981-03-05 - 1982-06-29; 01065157
    - Operational Policy - Water Supply and Urban Development - PWU - Tourism adivisory services - set, 1981-01-01 - 1983-12-31; 01065168
    - Operational Policy - Water Supply and Urban Development - PWU - Urban Development 1984 - 1986, 1984-01-09 - 1985-02-15; 01065169
    - Urban Projects - PUR - Tourism Advisory Services 1981 - 1983, 1981-04-24 - 1982-05-17; 01064464
    - Operational Policy - Water Supply and Urban - PWU - Urban Development 1981 - 1983, 1983-09-13 - 1983-10-25; 01057502
    - Operational Policy - Water Supply and Urban - PWU - Urban poverty - set, 1984-01-01 - 1986-12-31; 01057503
    - Operational Policy - Water Supply and Urban - PWU - Tourism advisor services - set, 1984-01-01 - 1986-12-31; 01057501
    - Operational Policy - Water Supply and Urban - PWU - Research - set, 1984-01-01 - 1986-12-31; 01057500
    - Operational Policy - Transportation Department - PTR - General Documents 1984 - 1986, 1982-01-28 - 1984-07-31; 01057498
    - Operational Policy - Transportation Department PTR - General 1984 - 1986, 1982-12-07 - 1986-03-24; 01057497
    - Transportation, Water and Telecommunications Department - PTWT - Telecommunications 1981 - 1983, 1981-01-06 - 1982-05-17; 01064453
    - Operational Policy - Water Supply and Urban - PUR - General - 1981 / 1983 Correspondence - Volume 1, 1981-01-19 - 1983-07-21; 01057530
    - Operational Policy - Water Supply and Urban - PWU - Water Supply and Sewerage - 1984 / 1986 Documents - Volume 1, 1991-02-01; 01057532
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTW - Water and Wastes - Documents - 1981 - 1983 - Volume 2, 1991-02-01; 30048786
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTW - Water and Wastes - Documents 1981 - 1983 - Volume 1, 1982-06-01 - 1983-02-28; 30048785
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTW - Water and Wastes 1981 - 1983, 1982-08-12 - 1983-07-07; 30048784
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTW - Transportations Documents 1981 - 1983, 1978-07-01 - 1983-01-28; 30048783
    - Operational Policy - P - Water Supply and Urban - PWU - Research Documents 1984 - 1986, 1984-05-01 - 1984-05-31; 30048841
    - Operational Policy - PWU - Urban Development Documents, volume 1, 1981 - 1983, 1981-01-01 - 1983-12-31; 30053113
    - Operational Policy - PWU - General Documents, volume 1, 1981 - 1983, 1981-01-01 - 1983-12-31; 30053115
    - Operational Policy - PWU - Urban Development Documents, volume 1, 1984 - 1986, 1984-01-01 - 1986-12-31; 30053114
    - Operational Policy - P - Water Supply and Urban - PUR - General Documents 1984 - 1986, 1985-04-05 - 1985-04-08; 30048836
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTR - Research Documents 1984 - 1986, 1986-02-01 - 1986-02-28; 30048834
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTR - Research 1984 - 1986, 1984-05-09 - 1986-02-26; 30048833
    - Urban Projects - PUR - Urban Poverty Documents 1981 - 1983, 1981-03-02 - 1982-01-12; 30048826
    - Transportation, Water and Telecommunications Department - PTWT - Water and Wastes 1981 - 1983, 1981-03-13 - 1982-05-25; 01064458
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTW - Research Documents 1981 - 1983, 1982-12-01 - 1982-12-31; 30048782
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTW - General 1981 - 1983, 1982-05-18 - 1983-06-14; 30048781
    - Urban Projects - PUR - Urban Poverty 1978 - 1980 - Volume 3, 1979-03-05 - 1980-07-30; 30048776
    - Urban Projects - PUR - Urban Poverty 1978 - 1980 - Volume 2, 1978-02-23 - 1979-01-24; 30048775
    - Urban Projects - PUR - Urban Poverty 1978 - 1980 - Volume 4, 1980-08-01 - 1980-12-05; 30048777
    - Poverty Income Levels - General - Ex Task I, 1975-07-25 - 1979-11-16; 30048780
    - Urban Projects - PUR - Urban Povery - Volume 2, 1978-01-10; 30048779
    - Urban Projects - PUR - Urban Povery - Volume 1, 1991-02-01; 30048778
    - Operational Policy - Urban - PUR - Tourism Advisory Services 1978 - 1980, 1979-10-30 - 1980-10-21; 01065164
    - Urban Projects - PUR - Urban Poverty 1978 - 1980 - Volume 1, 1978-01-04 - 1978-03-30; 01064465
    - Urban Projects - PUR - General Documents, 1978-05-01 - 1979-12-31; 01064463
    - Urban Projects - PUR - General 1978 - 1980 - Volume 1, 1978-01-24 - 1978-05-26; 01064462
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTWT - Water and Wastes 1978 - 1980 - Volume 1, 1978-02-06 - 1980-02-28; 01065160
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTW - Water and Wastes - Documents - Volume 1, 1977-08-01 - 1980-02-29; 01065154
    - Transportation, Water and Telecommunications Department - PTWT - Water and Wastes Documents 1978 - 1980, 1978-10-01 - 1980-05-31; 01064460
    - Transportation, Water and Telecommunications Department - PTWT - Transportation Documents 1978 - 1980, 1978-10-01 - 1980-01-01; 01064456
    - Transportation, Water and Telecommunications Department - PTWT - Transportation 1978 - 1980 - Volume 2, 1980-03-04 - 1980-11-25; 30048770
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTWT - Transportation Documents, 1979-01-10 - 1980-10-31; 01065159
    - Transportation, Water and Telecommunications Department - PTWT - Transportation 1978 - 1980 - Volume 1, 1978-02-14 - 1980-01-22; 01064455
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTWT - Telecommunications, 1977-12-08 - 1980-08-01; 01065158
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTWT - General, 1978-10-03 - 1980-12-22; 01065156
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTW - General 1978 - 1980, 1980-05-06 - 1980-06-24; 01065151
    - Transportation, Water and Telecommunications Department - PTWT - Telecommunications Documents, 1975-04-25 - 1980-07-08; 01064454
    - Transportation, Water and Telecommunications Department - PTWT - Research Documents 1978 - 1980, 1978-09-01 - 1978-09-30; 01064452
    - Transportation, Water and Telecommunications Department - PTWT - Port Accounts Documents 1978 - 1980, 1980-05-01 - 1980-05-31; 01064451
    - Transportation, Water and Telecommunications Department - PTWT - Port Accounting and Tarriff Study, 1979-02-09 - 1980-09-10; 01064450
    - Transportation, Water and Telecommunications Department - PTWT - General Documents, 1978-04-05 - 1980-06-30; 01064448
    - Sector - Urban Development - 1987 / 1989 Correspondence - Volume 1, 1986-01-14 - 1987-05-21; 01156139
    - Sector - Telecommunications - 1987 / 1989 Correspondence - Volume 1, 1987-02-13 - 1987-03-11; 01156136
    - Sector - Transportation - 1987 / 1989 Correspondence - Volume 1, 1987-01-08 - 1987-04-06; 01156138
    - Sector - Water Supply - 1987 / 1989 Correspondence - Volume 1, 1987-01-20 - 1987-07-08; 01156140
    - Urban Projects - PUR - General 1978 - 1980 - Volume 3, 1979-06-07 - 1980-12-23; 30048774
    - Urban Projects - PUR - General 1978 - 1980 - Volume 2, 1978-03-28 - 1979-05-31; 30048773
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTWT - Water and Wastes 1978 - 1980 - Volume 2, 1980-03-07 - 1980-12-17; 30048771
    - INP - Telecommunications - 1987 / 1989 Correspondence - Volume 1, 1987-01-13 - 1987-06-03; 01178855
  - Liaison records, 1978 to 1983; WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_106-01-02; 1.14 linear feet of textual records
    The series consist of records related to liaison with organizations external to the Bank. This includes correspondence maintained by Transportation, Water, and Telecommunications Department (TWT) related to the joint United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) - World Bank Water and Sanitation Program from 1978, and correspondence maintained by TWT and WUD related to the joint World Health Organization (WHO) / World Bank Cooperative Program, which also focused on water and sanitation, from 1977 to 1987.
    - Transportation, Water and Telecommunications Department - PTWT - United Nations Development Program [UNDP] - Cooperative Program, 1978-03-06; 01064457
    - Operational Policy - Water Supply and Urban Development - PWU - WHO / IBRD Cooperative Program - set, 1981-01-01 - 1983-12-31; 01065171
    - Operational Policy - Transportation - PTWT - World Health Organization [WHO] / International Bank for Reconstruction and Development [IBRD] Cooperative Program 1981 - 1983, 1981-04-01 - 1982-05-17; 01065161
    - Transportation, Water and Telecommunications Department - PTWT - World Health Organization [ WHO] - Cooperative Program 1978 - 1980, 1979-03-06 - 1980-04-11; 01064461
    - UNDP/INT/77/021 - Study of Construction Standards and Methods Appropriate for Simple Building Accomodation Requirements - Correspondence, 1977-08-25 - 1980-05-23; 01180268
    - UNDP/INT/86/006 - Urban Development Strategies - 1984 / 1986 - Correspondence - Volume 1, 1986-02-21; 01181093